support and resistance once you master
them making money in the markets becomes
extremely easy however I have discovered
that the mass majority of Traders out
there have no idea how this works they
have absolutely no idea how to interpret
them and even less how to use them in
their advantage to make money and in
this video I'm going to teach you the
most basic thing that every single
Trader should know how to use support
and resistance to your advantage I'm
going to give you examples of Trades
that I have personally made numbers like
these and even these by simply using
support and resistance the right way so
we have to really understand what does
support and resistance mean so let me
explain support and resistance are areas
where we are waiting for the market to
get there this is where the areas
consist of buyers and sellers once price
gets to these areas so what support
looks like is once price is declining
into a level of support and then the
buyers come into the market and then
push price to the upside and then
resistance is when when price is heading
to the upside it hits a resistance level
then sellers come into the market and
then take price to the downside it is
literally as simple as that it's exactly
what it said in the name support is When
Buyers come in and then hold price up
and then resistance is when sellers come
into the market and push price down so
now that we understand what is a support
level and what is a resistance level why
are these areas so important why does
everybody talk about it and why are they
so important for the basic key
foundations of a successful Trader and
there's so important because these are
the areas where price can have a
reaction from in your favor without
having any obstacle in its way not
letting it get to your takeprofit faster
than it should be let me explain so
let's pretend that price is heading to
the downside and we have a support level
down here we are destined to wait for
price to come to this support level and
then have a reaction from it so then we
head up to the upside this support level
once price gets here and we have a
rejection this support level is going to
give us the impulsive move for price to
continue to head to the upside without
having any slow down because we have
reached the level of support so now it's
going to have a reaction from it and
head to the upside faster than if it
were to not be at a support level and
then the resistance is literally the
complete opposite price is heading to
the upside and then we are waiting for
price to hit the area of Interest or the
zone as resistance where there's a lot
of sellers in the market once price hits
this resistance level then we use it as
a resistance to then head to the
downside in our favor faster than any
other way because we are going with the
sellers from the market and support and
resistance might also be known as area
of Interest so let's say you're looking
to buy you would have the support area
as your area of interest and if you're
looking to then sell your resistance
would be your area of Interest so area
of interest can go for both support or
it can go for resistance it just depends
for what you're looking for if you're
looking to buy then you have a support
as your area of interest if you're
looking to then sell then you have your
resistance as your area of interest and
to make all this super simple it's
literally the areas where a bunch of
buyers and sellers come into the market
and whoever wins then pushes price in
that favor so if you're at a support
level the buyers win they push price up
if you're at a resistance the sellers
win they push price down now are all the
supports and resistance the same and the
answer is no they're actually completely
different
support is used as support and
resistance is used as resistance you
cannot use them against each other you
can't use a resistance level to then buy
you can't use a support level to then
sell almost think about it as a
resistance level as the roof and if this
were to be the roof how are you going to
buy right into the roof like let's say
you are 6 fet tall and you have a 7t
roof you can't jump cuz you're going to
hit your head that's not the goal let's
say you're in a twot pool you can't dive
into a twoot pool because you're going
to hurt yourself so you can't sell into
support you need to use them as what
they are supposed to be if you are in a
twoot pool this is where then you jump
from if you're at a resistance then this
is where you then go down from so now
that we understand that we have
different types of areas of Interest we
have psychological areas of Interest we
have strong areas of Interest we have
weak areas of Interest all of this Falls
inside the area interest category and
it's actually very simple to understand
let me explain let's first start off
with what is and what is not a support
and resistance so first of all very
simple example of a psychological level
is literally you go to the Chart you
find whatever currency Peri your trading
and then you look at the numbers that
are to your right hand side and there
you find any round psychological level
for example
17,000 1.8 th000 1.6 th000 any single
number that is a round psychological
level is also considered an area of
Interest I personally like combining
both but I will show you a little bit
more of this later in the video when we
actually get into the charts next is a
strong area of Interest a strong area of
interest is when you have more than
three to four taps at that time frame in
that area of Interest the stronger the
area of Interest the more Taps meaning
the more rejections meaning the more
it's respected meaning once price gets
that area the odds of you winning that
trade are a lot more in your favor
because in the past it's done it more
times than not and the further you go
back into the chart and the more Taps
and rejections it has the better next we
have weak area of Interest a weak area
of interest is something that it has
under three rejections from that area
which is not an ideal area because
there's not much data indicating that
once price gets there it's going to have
a strong rejection in your favor with
your trade and lastly one of my
favorites that I use every single day in
trading is is the break and retest so
it's actually way simpler than you can
ever imagine break and retest literally
consist of price breaking and then
retesting the area it's that simple
let's say you have a resistance level
and price gets to it and you don't have
a rejection so not enough sellers come
into the market to push price down price
then breaks that area it come back it
retests it it uses it as support and
then it heads to the upside it's
literally as simple as I'm explaining it
but I'm going to get into more detail
now when we get into the charts so what
is a support a support is an area that
has more than three touches now an area
support can be found on any single time
frame can be found on the 1 hour 4H hour
daily weekly on any time frame obviously
the higher the time frame the more
respected this support level will be
because if price gets to a daily support
level and it's had let's say five
rejections for example this is good
because the daily time time frame takes
a lot longer to move so it's a lot more
respected than let's say a 1H hour area
of Interest or a support level with five
touches because the 1 hour has a lot
more movement and it could break and not
respect that level compared to the Daily
time frame so a support level is One's
price has more than three Taps of price
being held above that support level as
you can see in this example right here
so now what is not a level of support
and it's lit
the complete opposite of what is right
here a level of support is price that
does not have more than three rejections
it's that there's no clear indication
and clear rejection from this level of
support if price is just breaking above
and under the zone and not respecting it
to the T in a very tight and square Zone
this is not a support level and will not
be respected so what is a resistance
level literally the same thing just flip
the chart around once price gets to an
area and it has has more than three
touches and it's a very tight Zone
that's a level of resistance and what is
not a level of resistance the same exact
thing as support an area that price is
constantly breaking through not
respecting it and no clear indication
that it is respecting that tight box of
the zone so now let's actually get to
the charts where I'm going to show you a
strong level of support and resistance a
weak level of support and resistance a
strong level of a psychological area and
then a breaking retest how I personally
use it every single day to make a bunch
of money in the market so let me show
you guys so let's get started here on
the charts so this right here is the
Japanese candlesticks form of reading
charts you guys can see right here this
are the Candlestick patterns that you're
seeing currently right now in the market
and we're going to set up multiple
examples on what is a strong level of
support and resistance so before we go
into the candlesticks let me just get
started with the line chart so you guys
understand very clearly so in this
example right here I'm going to be
showing to you guys what is a very clean
and clear level of support so this is
what we would call an ideal level of
support So as you guys can see right
here this Market is obviously headed to
the upside but there is a level of
support right in front of your face and
as soon as you spot it you can see that
it is a level of support because it has
more than three touches so this right
here is considered a valid level of
support not a strong one but definitely
a valid so as you can see right here we
have one tap we also have a second tap
and then this would be our third tap
right here making this a valid level of
support so now we now that we know that
once price comes back into this area we
could be interested in buying a trade
because we are because we're having a
high probability of this trade heading
to the upside from this level of support
because we've done it three times in the
past so the odds of it doing a fourth
are very high especially if the trend is
heading to the upside so for this
example right here this is what we would
consider a valid level of support and we
would be taking the trade on the fourth
touch of the level of support you're not
looking to take the trade on the
potential reaction from the third tab
you guys need to be very key with this
be very selective once you have a
confirmation rejection as the third one
we would then be entering on the fourth
one as our area of Interest or level of
support on the trade so now that we
understand what is a valid level of
support what is a valid level of
resistance it is literally the exact
same thing just flip it around so we're
going to do a quick flip around right
here which we're going to invert the
scale and as you can notice it's
literally the same exact price all we
simply have done is invert the scale a
lot of you guys out there might be
better at identifying support or
identifying resistance if you ever have
any trouble right click on this line
right here and you just simply click
invert scale so for this example right
here it's the same exact thing once you
have one one tab two tab three tab we'
be looking to then sell on the fourth
top because the odds of it going down
from here a lot higher because we've had
multiple rejections from this area so
this is what we would consider a valid
area of interest because it has had more
than three Taps from the level of
resistance so this is a valid and
respected level of resistance so now
moving on we understand what is a valid
level of support now I'm going to be
showing to you guys what is a strong
area of support this is what you want to
see the more of this that you see the
better the odds that you're going to win
the next trade so this right here is our
same chart that we were looking at
earlier and let's just draw more price
through it let's just simply come in
through here and let's just look messy
how the charts would look to a newb and
it'd be a bit confused right so this
right
here is what we would consider a strong
area of Interest why because we are
having more than one tap so for this
example you can see how we have one tap
right here we then have our same exact
second and third tap and you can tell
right here things get a little bit
different now we are having a resistance
be considered a tap and you may be
asking yourself why and this is because
it is confirming that this is a strong
support support level used as resistance
in the past and whenever we are under
it's used as resistance whenever we are
above is used as support So for this
example we have 1 2 3 4 5 six rejections
from this level of Support also known as
area of interest and the Simplicity of
it is that the more Taps the better the
more rejections and reactions you have
from the Zone the better it's meaning
that it is more respected if you can go
up to 20 30 rejections the better that
means that you are having a very strong
and valid level of support now do the
resistance Taps count as Taps towards
the points of the level of support and
the answer is yes because this is a
respected movement in price and data so
whenever price is under it is rejecting
and whenever price is above it is
rejecting and for this example right
here we are clearly above the level of
support or the area of Interest so the
odds of it going up are very high
because whenever we are above we're
rejecting and whenever we are under we
are rejecting so for this example the
odds of it going up are much higher than
going down simply because we are above
it so the more Taps you get into the
area the better the tabs could be under
it or it can be above you just have to
make sure they are tight in this Zone
this right here would not be considered
a top this is is way too far from the
area of Interest so this would not be
considered six Taps this would only be
considered four taps towards the area of
interest because there is clearly only
four rejections so the more Taps that
you get of this area the stronger and
the better and the odds are you
succeeding and making money with this
trade now what is a very strong level of
resistance the same exact thing just
flip it around we're going to right
click on these buttons here going to
Simply click invert scale and it is the
exact same thing the more Taps we have
of this area now this is a area of
interest to then sell because we are
obviously in now a downwards market so
you can see here and now since we are
under this area we're going to be
looking to then sell when we are above
this area we're looking to buy when we
are under this area we are looking to
sell it is literally that simple you put
the Zone the more Taps it has the
stronger if you are above that zone you
like to buy if you are under that zone
you like to sell it's that simple next
I'm going to be talking to you about the
round psychological areas of Interest or
support and resistance a lot of people
use this more on the lower time frames I
personally use it in correlation with
the area of interest on the higher time
frame but more on that later in this
video and it's very simple this is
probably the simplest thing I can ever
explain it's literally around
psychological level so you can get a
line and throw it anywhere in the chart
literally I can just look random just
boom just throw it in the middle of the
chart and your goal is to get this
number right here as close as you can to
every 500 so for example this right now
is
171 441 if you simply delete the
441 and you put a 5
71500 that is considered around
psychological area of interest can also
come into here just throw it randomly
double tap the chart and let's just to a
round psychological level
171,000 we can also come into here again
and put one at down here doesn't matter
throw it anywhere in the chart for
example right here the the nearest 100
is
172 and now this is the area of Interest
a lot of people use this because Banks
and institutions they close their
positions at these round psychological
levels think about it if you're going to
be closing multi-billions of dollars
you're not going to do it at a random
price point of let's say 1715 32 makes
no sense you want to close all of your
positions on around psychological level
like this one so Traders use that in
their advantage because now they can mix
that with the level of support and
resistance and at those areas a lot of
positions are being closed because banks
are liquidating their orders and that's
where the sellers come into the market
and then move price down so let's say
you're having a movement to the upside
like this all the banks close their
position so now the sellers come into
the market and boom it pushes the price
down and once price comes down here and
bankers liquidate all their positions
new buyers come in and then push price
to the upside so this is just an added
Confluence that it is to support and
resistance so now I'm going to show you
some examples of a strong level of
support or resistance on the Candlestick
chart obviously we're going to be
trading on candlesticks I just was
showing you guys very simply what it is
like on the line chart so let me show
you what it looks like on the charts so
this right here this is what is
considered a strong level of support and
resistance so let me show you how I
would actually mark up the points or the
TOs of this area right here so for
example this right here would be one tap
this right here would be a second tap so
then this would be a third tap this
right here would be a fourth tap right
here this right here would be a six s
and then eight so all of these right
here well then nine we can't miss this
last one right so this right here is a
strong level of support and resistance
and you can almost tell every single
time we get to this Zone we have a
reaction immediately when we're above
and immediately when we are under now
you may be asking yourself why that is
because we are on the daily time frame
the higher the time frame the more
respected the zone is going to be
literally every single time we come to
this one we're above we head to the
upside if you notice here when we we're
above we reacted but then we completely
broke through it after and then we
rejected to head to the the downside we
came to it again rejected to the
downside so whenever price is under it's
going to then sell whenever price is
above it is going to then buy the higher
the time frame the better now let me
show you what is a weak level of support
and resistance and how it is not
respected so this right here is not a
strong level of support or resistance as
you can see there's maybe one clear
rejection maybe two of you want to get
pushy and then three it's not ideal
because they're not clear points and
look how something so simple as moving
this box up or down can make a complete
and total change on the area of Interest
so as you can see right here it doesn't
look clear doesn't look like there's a
lot of nice rejections if I simply move
this box slightly down you can see how
now everything completely changes you
can see how now we have 1 2 3 4 4 5 6 7
8 9 10 Taps from this area that is all
you guys are missing just a little bit
more of clarity and looking at the
markets in a very simple and effective
way so you can spot areas of Interest
like this all of the time this is a
great example whenever you we are under
we are selling whenever we are above we
are buying whenever we are under we are
selling this is a classic strong level
of support that is also used as
resistance so as you can see support and
resistance is is not anything difficult
or something you should be scared of in
the market it's something you need and
as you can see in that last example
right there the simpler you make it the
better and you can see how something so
small by simply moving the are of
interest just down by a little bit you
can have so much more clarity and
looking into the market and that is what
I do with all of my students inside the
set and forget where they're making
anywhere from $1,000 to
$11,500 a week as a beginner set and
forget Trader they come not
understanding anything and by simply
getting on the weekly calls with me and
all of the other students I bring so
much Clarity to any questions or
concerns you may have because it's what
I do I change people's life with set and
forget that's making students have
anywhere from ,000 to $11,500 a week in
the first 3 months using the set and
forget strategy if you want to know more
about what is set and forget and how
would this even make sense for you I
have a link in the description below
where it explains to you what set and
forget consists of completely cuz I know
it might seem intimidating seeing
students leaving their jobs and making
anywhere from $1,000 to $11,500 a week
but it has completely changed my life
and taking me from Dunkin Donuts to the
life that I'm living like today so you
want to know more about what set and
forget is and how you can use it to
either make an extra side income from
Trading or to become a full-time Trader
watch the link in the description below
there's a video there for you that
explains everything about what set and
forget is and how you can become part of
the setting forget family thank you guys
for watching the video all the way to
the end make sure you like comment and
subscribe and I'll see you guys in the
next video